

PROFILE

I am a full stack developer from Fort Mill South Carolina. I develop websites using frameworks such as vue and react. I have experience working as a solo contractor for a local and as a member of a team of a nation wide staffing company. I am graduating from BYUI in April 2024 with a BS in Software Engineering and a certificate in Web Development. In my free time I enjoy mountain unicycling with my friends, and Camping in Lynnville NC. Feel free to check out my website below where you can learn more and view my full portfolio.

CONTACT

PHONE: 8035042034

EMAIL:

skylerjsimpson@gmail.com

WEBSITE:

skylersimpson.netlify.app



SKYLER SIMPSON

Full Stack Web Developer

EDUCATION

Brigham Young University Idaho 2020-2024

BS, Software Engineering, Certified in Web Development

SCHOOL EXPERIENCE

Web Development:

I had the opportunity to explore different avenues of programming in college. Through my exploration I found a love for web development and chose to focus my studies there. I took many classes focused on Frontend development, backend development, Full stack, web design, and advanced CSS.

Front-End:

In my various front-end classes I gained experience in frameworks such as react and vue. I made my own custom components to sove complex problems and learned how to find pre-existing libraries that would fit my use cases. I worked with tools such as Netlify, Heroku, and Vercel for deployment. I explored options for styling such as CSS, SCSS, and Tailwind.

Back-End:

In the backend courses that I had I worked extensively with node. I became proficient at deploying RESTful API's that used SQL and noSQL databases. I used various hosting services and database tools such as render, MongoDB, AWS, pgAdmin, and mySQL,. I took particular interest in ORM tools such as sequelize and prisma for managing relational databases. I became familiar with organizational tools such as swagger to document my API's.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Stone Crest Suites: Web Full Stack Developer Aug 2023-Jan 2024

- Developed a full stack webpage that allowed users to reserve office space
- Implemented director privileges, allowing directors to customize the entire website and edit the data in any way they need.

OnDiem Dental Staffing: Front End Developer Jan 2024–PRESENT

- Contributed to the creation of OnDiems staffing website through sprint plannings and ticket completions.
- Used Vue to create new components and update existing components.
- Gained experience working on a larger development team and working for a company.

SKILLS

HTML	CSS	JavaScript	Vue
Node	Sequelize	React	TailWind
ORMs	Figma	C++	GitHub